Guide to the Beach Archive ca.1962-1973 MSS 5 MSS.005
Fales Library and Special Collections
Beach Archive
ca. 1962-1973
Fales Library and Special Collections
Beach Books
MSS.005
0.25 Linear Feet (1 Box)
The Beach Archive is a collection of correspondence and manuscripts submitted to the editors of Beach Books, Claude Pelieu and Mary Beach, between 1962 and 1973. Collection highlights include manuscripts and letters written by Carl Solomon, Allen Ginsberg, Allen de Loach, Gregory Corso, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, John Giorno, Timothy Leary, and Peter Orlovsky.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open without restrictions. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Scope and Content Note
The Beach Archive is a collection of correspondence and manuscripts submitted to the editors of Beach Books, Claude Pelieu and Mary Beach, from 1962 to 1973. Collection highlights include manuscripts and letters written by Carl Solomon, Allen Ginsberg, Allen de Loach, Gregory Corso, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, John Giorno, Timothy Leary, and Peter Orlovsky.
Arrangement
The Beach Archive is arranged alphabetically.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence and Manuscripts
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Poets, American -- 20th century.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); American literature -- 20th century.; Art, Modern |y 20th century |v Periodicals.; Manuscripts for publication.; Literature, Experimental |x Periodicals.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Postcards.; Authors, American -- 20th century.; Giorno, John; Pélieu, Claude; Orlovsky, Peter, 1933-2010; Leary, Timothy, 1920-1996; Corso, Gregory; Beach, Mary, 1919-2006; Beach Books; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence; De Loach, Allen
- Series I: Correspondence and Manuscripts
  Scope and Contents note
  Series 1 contains one box of correspondence to the editors Claude Pelieu and Mary Beach. Noted correspondents include Carl Solomon, Allen Ginsberg, Allen de Loach, Gregory Corso, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, John Giorno, Timothy Leary, and Peter Orlovsky. Series 1 also contains manuscripts submitted by Carl Solomon and Allen Ginsberg.
  - Julian Beck, Bonnie Bresmer, and Gregory Corso, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Giorno, Timothy Leary, Peter Orlovsky, and Charles Plymel, 1971-1972; undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ed Sanders, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aldan Van Buskirk, Ken Weaver, John Weiners, 1970, 1972; undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allen Ginsberg, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Allen Ginsberg "Television Was a Baby", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Allen Ginsberg, and French translations by Mary Beach, ca. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Carl Solomon, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Carl Solomon, various manuscripts, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Related materials, Carl Solomon, Ann Solomon, Cordola Koshembahr, and Allen DeLoach., 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)